import { Question } from "../components/MovieQuiz";

export const gotData: Question[] = [
  {
    question: "Who sits on the Iron Throne at the end of Game of Thrones?",
    options: [
      "Daenerys Targaryen",
      "Jon Snow",
      "Bran Stark",
      "Tyrion Lannister",
    ],
    answer: "Bran Stark",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Arya Stark's sword?",
    options: ["Needle", "Oathkeeper", "Longclaw", "Ice"],
    answer: "Needle",
  },
  {
    question: "Who kills the Night King?",
    options: ["Jon Snow", "Bran Stark", "Arya Stark", "Daenerys Targaryen"],
    answer: "Arya Stark",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the ancestral home of House Stark?",
    options: ["Winterfell", "King's Landing", "The Eyrie", "Casterly Rock"],
    answer: "Winterfell",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is known as the 'Mother of Dragons'?",
    options: [
      "Daenerys Targaryen",
      "Cersei Lannister",
      "Sansa Stark",
      "Melisandre",
    ],
    answer: "Daenerys Targaryen",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which character is known for saying, 'You know nothing, Jon Snow'?",
    options: ["Ygritte", "Arya Stark", "Catelyn Stark", "Brienne of Tarth"],
    answer: "Ygritte",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the motto of House Lannister?",
    options: [
      "Hear Me Roar",
      "Winter is Coming",
      "Fire and Blood",
      "We Do Not Sow",
    ],
    answer: "Hear Me Roar",
  },
  {
    question: "Who is the eldest Stark child?",
    options: ["Robb Stark", "Jon Snow", "Sansa Stark", "Arya Stark"],
    answer: "Robb Stark",
  },
  {
    question: "Who kills King Joffrey?",
    options: [
      "Olenna Tyrell",
      "Tyrion Lannister",
      "Sansa Stark",
      "Jaime Lannister",
    ],
    answer: "Olenna Tyrell",
  },
  {
    question: "Which house's sigil is a direwolf?",
    options: [
      "House Stark",
      "House Lannister",
      "House Targaryen",
      "House Baratheon",
    ],
    answer: "House Stark",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the name of Jon Snow's direwolf?",
    options: ["Ghost", "Nymeria", "Summer", "Shaggydog"],
    answer: "Ghost",
  },
];
